Krishna Teja Tangaturi

Lead Android Developer & Architect

Gifted Android Developer offering more than 10 years of experience in demanding environments and broad range of industries including e-commerce, wearables, education, digital-twins, remote inspections/audits. Skilled in directing development with creative and performance-oriented approach. Well-organized and customerfocused with proven skills in project management and team leadership.

Work History

2020-10 -Current

Lead Android Developer

PSC Biotech, Hyderabad, Telangana

- Developed apps for Remote Inspections and Audits on Google Glass EE2 and Realwear wearables
- Ported zoom meetings on to Google Glass EE2 and Realwear
- Over-The-Air update mechanisms and MDM for Google Glass and Realwear wearables
- Helped to automate biotech plant operations with OCR and Image analytics
- Used critical thinking to break down problems, evaluate solutions and make decisions.
- Integrated Insta 360 video stream into zoom meetings for remote conferences

2018-01 -2020-09

Director of Platform

XYZ Innovations Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Managed 4 projects simultaneously and met deadlines on time.
- Contributed to vision and high-level technical concepts spanning technology and business.
- Executing product backlog, sprint backlog, roadmap and release plan.
- Supporting team by reducing churn and waste, removing blockers, escalating issues and helping to mentor and grow team members.
- Cultivating highly effective relationships with internal

Contact

Address

Miyapur Hyderabad, TG, 500034

Phone

9676316323

E-mail

teja.tangaturi@gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com /in/ktthealmighty/

Skills

Android (SDK)

••••• Excellent

Java

Excellent

Kotlin

Very Good

NodeJS

Very Good

SwiftUI

Good

Firebase

Very Good

Gradle

business partners like product management, technical leads, operations, service and support

 Hands on involvement in Maps, Collaboration module, User & Role management, Email engine, Chat module, Attendance tracking, Digital twins, MSA, Docker and deployments

2015-12 - Lead Android Developer

2017-12

MySmartPrice Web Technology Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Collaborated with internal and external teams Product Managers, Engineers, Designers, and
 Marketers to conceptualize, build, test and realize
 new features.
- Implementing complex User Interfaces for MySmartPrice Android application.
- Payment Gateway integration using RazorPay
- Standardized and enforced coding best practices, including optimizing apps for performance.
- Mentored and guided team of 4 members ensuring all were trained in product knowledge and capable of performing assigned duties.

2014-10 - Senior Android Developer 2015-11

Hug Innovations Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Being lone android developer for company very quickly jumped onboard and took tull responsibility of development and operation of app
- Implemented Bluetooth communication between android mobile and wearable device.
- Implemented Google maps customizations and places/near-by locations services
- Developed Custom graphs/charts.
- Implemented push notification setup handling over 10k notifications/day.

2012-01 - Android Developer 2014-10

Edutor Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Hyderabad, Telangana

- Mobile Device Management Controlling around
 500 android devices over internet.
- Usage Tracking Tracking user actions and content usage statistics and updating them on to cloud.



AWS



Angular 4+



Docker



MongoDB



Micro Service Architecture



Build releases



Software

Android Studio



Eclipse



Visual Studio Code



Very Good

Source Tree



Xcode



- Teacher controlled student tab Environment where teacher controls students tablets from his/her tablet
- Over-The-Air upgrades.
- Mobile Device Management (MDM)
- Developed and installed several security models and policies on android devices.

Education

2010-07 - Master of Science: Information Technology
2012-04 International Institute Of Information Technology Hyderabad

2006-08 - Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

Dhirubhai Ambani Institute Of Information Techno. -Ahmedabad

Languages

English



Hindi



Telugu

